https://www.cefcu.com/privacy-policy.html

Skip to main content.
Free Checking
Save with CEFCU Checking, an account that benefits you... not your financial institution.
Student Loans
Dining. Travel. Fuel. Fun.
The CEFCU Mastercard® makes it easy.
Protect Your Car
Ask about coverage for auto repairs, roadside assistance, and more. Get Coverage
Electronic Payment Services
If you are using a screen reader or other auxiliary aid and are having problems using this website, please contact us at 1.800.633.7077.
Visit our accessibility help page.
CEFCU’s Privacy Policy
Citizens Equity First Credit Union ("CEFCU") and its wholly-owned subsidiary, CEFCU Financial Services®, Inc., (together, "we" or "our") are committed to keeping personal financial information about you, your accounts, and your transactions confidential as required by federal and state laws and the CEFCU Bylaws. This Privacy Policy applies to all visitors, users, and others who do not reside in the State of California ("you" or "your"). Visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of California see CEFCU's Privacy Policy for California Residents. This Privacy Policy explains our privacy policies and practices regarding the information we collect from or about you, how we protect that information, the sharing of that information to better serve your financial needs, and your choices about our sharing that information.
FACTS
WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
Why?
Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this California Privacy Policy carefully to understand what we do.
What?
The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us.
This information can include:
Social Security number and income
Credit-based insurance scores
Account balances and payment history
Credit history and assets
How?
All financial companies need to share members’/customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their members’/customers’ personal information; the reasons we choose to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
Reasons we can share your personal information
Does CEFCU share?
Can you limit this sharing?
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus
YES
NO
For our marketing purposes – to offer our products and services to you
YES
NO
For joint marketing with other financial companies
YES
NO
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your transactions and experiences
YES
NO
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your creditworthiness or insurability
YES
YES
For our affiliates to market to you
YES
YES
For nonaffiliates to market to you
NO
WE DON’T SHARE
To limit our sharing, mail the Mail-in Form (PDF, 74 KB)
REMEMBER: If you previously opted out, you do not need to do so again. Your choice(s) will apply until you tell us to change your choice(s).
Please note:If you are a new member/customer, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent you an initial privacy notice. When you are no longer our member/policyholder, we continue to share your information as described in this California Privacy Policy.However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  You may do so by writing us a letter and mailing it to:Citizens Equity First Credit Union Compliance Department 5401 W. Dirksen Parkway P.O. Box 1715 Peoria, IL 61607
Questions? Call toll-free 1.800.633.7077 or go to cefcu.com.
Who we are
Who is providing this Privacy Policy? CEFCU and CEFCU Financial Services, Inc.
What we do
How does CEFCU protect my personal information?
To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards, secured files and buildings, and restricted access to your personal information.
How does CEFCU collect my personal information?
We collect your personal information, for example, when you:
open an account or deposit money
apply for insurance
pay your bills or apply for a loan
pay insurance premiums
use your credit or debit card
We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.
Why can’t I limit all sharing?
Federal law gives you the right to limit only:
sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your creditworthiness
affiliates from using your information to market to you
sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you
State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.
See below for more on your rights under state law.
What happens when I limit sharing for an account/policy I hold jointly with someone else?
Your choices will apply to everyone on your account/policy – unless you tell us otherwise.
Definitions
Affiliates
Companies related by common ownership or control: They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.
Our affiliates are:
CEFCU Financial Services, Inc.
MEMBERS™ Trust Company
Nonaffiliates
Companies not related by common ownership or control: They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.
Nonaffiliates we share with can include financial service providers, such as securities broker-dealers and insurance companies or agents; and non-financial companies, such as retailers, direct marketing companies, airlines, and publishers.
Joint marketing
A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.
Our joint marketing partners include securities broker-dealers and insurance companies.
Information Collection
We do not collect any personally identifiable information on our website unless you submit the information or give your consent. We use website monitoring software to gather aggregate information about our visitors’ browsing activities in order to improve our website and better serve our members/consumers. We use this data to analyze trends, track visitor movement, and gather demographic information. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. We provide calculators and other online tools to assist visitors in making financial decisions. These tools do not collect or store any information entered by web visitors. Applications for services, accounts, or loans you submit through Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan and forms that you complete and submit on our website are protected in accord with this Privacy Policy.
We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under age 13 on our website.
When you log in to Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan, your identity is no longer anonymous; each username corresponds to a specific member/consumer and that information is collected and retained. To ensure the security of your accounts and information, all actions are monitored and tracked. You should never share your username and/or password with another person to ensure the security and privacy of your accounts and information. Refer to the Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan disclosures for complete privacy, security, and usage information.
Security Procedures
We understand the confidential and secure nature of your personal and financial data and have multiple security measures in place. Applications for services, account(s) or loan(s) that you submit through Online Banking, Open an Account, or Apply for a Loan and forms that you complete and submit on our website are submitted through secure, encrypted web pages. You can verify the security of a web page by looking for the “locked padlock” icon which most browsers display as a sign of a secure web page. To ensure the encryption of your web visit, you should ensure that you are using the most current web browser available. When you have logged in to Online Banking, Open an Account, or Apply for a Loan, all transactions and information are secure. We utilize the latest in technology to monitor Online Banking, Open an Account, and Apply for a Loan activity to protect your transactions and information. Built-in security measures include a session time-out (your Online Banking, Open an Account, or Apply for a Loan session will automatically log out after a period of inactivity), log in error lockout (after repeated incorrect log in attempts), and multi-factor authentication to verify your identity before you can log in.
Cookies
In order to provide certain Web-based services and to make your online experience more personalized, we may use cookies as part of our interaction with your Internet browser. A cookie is a very small piece of information stored on your local computer so it can later be read by our Web server. We use cookies to display information more effectively to you and to gather data about usage of our website. Cookies allow us to collect technical and navigational information — such as browser type, time spent on our website, and pages visited or track activity relating to our online promotions. This information is anonymous and does not include personal information. We retain, aggregate, monitor, and analyze the use of our website so we can continually improve the design, usability, and functionality to better serve you.
You can disable and delete cookies by accessing your browser’s preferences menu; however, you should be aware that when cookies are disabled, other online account services we provide, like Online Banking, may not work properly. For more information on working with cookies, consult the Help function of your browser.
Links to Other Websites
We are committed to providing you with the most complete information possible to help you make sound financial decisions. As a convenience to you, we may link from our website to other websites or Internet resources operated by third parties. When you link from our website to a third-party website, the linked website will appear in a new browser window or an alert will appear to notify you that you are leaving our website.
Links to third-party websites are solely for informational purposes and should not be construed as our endorsement or guarantee of the information or services provided on the linked website. We do not control third-party websites and are not responsible for the content on linked websites. Third-party website privacy, security, and other policies may differ from this Privacy Policy. Please review a linked website’s policies before providing personal information on that website.
Interruption of Service
At certain times, cefcu.com, Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan may be unavailable due to system maintenance or circumstances beyond our control. We conduct frequent and regular backups of your information and utilize redundant information practices to protect your information from being lost, altered, or corrupted due to unforeseen equipment malfunctions.
Changes to Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy on our website and update the effective date. Your continued use of our website or any product or service we provide following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.
Contact Information
If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:
Citizens Equity First Credit Union             Compliance Department             P.O. Box 1715             Peoria, IL 61656-9989
Effective Date: January 1, 2020.
CEFCU’s Privacy Policy for California Residents
CEFCU’s Privacy Policy for California Residents
Citizens Equity First Credit Union (“CEFCU”) and its wholly-owned subsidiary, CEFCU Financial Services®, Inc., (together, “we” or “our”) are committed to keeping personal financial information about you, your accounts, and your transactions confidential as required by federal and state laws and the CEFCU Bylaws. This Privacy Policy for California Residents (“California Privacy Policy”) applies to all visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of California (“you” or “your”). This California Privacy Policy explains our privacy policies and practices regarding the information we collect from or about you, how we protect that information, the sharing of that information to better serve your financial needs, and your choices about our sharing that information.  We adopt this California Privacy Policy to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”) and any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this California Privacy Policy. If you have a disability, please visit our Accessibility Help page at https://www.cefcu.com/accessibility-help.html.
FACTS
WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
Why?
Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this California Privacy Policy carefully to understand what we do.
What?
The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us.
This information can include:
Social Security number and income
Credit-based insurance scores
Account balances and payment history
Credit history and assets
How?
All financial companies need to share members’/customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their members’/customers’ personal information; the reasons we choose to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
Reasons we can share your personal information
Does CEFCU share?
Can you limit this sharing?
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus
YES
NO
For our marketing purposes – to offer our products and services to you
YES
NO
For joint marketing with other financial companies
YES
NO
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your transactions and experiences
YES
NO
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your creditworthiness or insurability
YES
YES
For our affiliates to market to you
YES
YES
For nonaffiliates to market to you
NO
WE DON’T SHARE
To limit our sharing, mail the Mail-in Form (PDF, 74 KB)
REMEMBER: If you previously opted out, you do not need to do so again. Your choice(s) will apply until you tell us to change your choice(s).
Please note:If you are a new member/customer, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent you an initial privacy notice. When you are no longer our member/policyholder, we continue to share your information as described in this California Privacy Policy.However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  You may do so by writing us a letter and mailing it to:Citizens Equity First Credit Union Compliance Department 5401 W. Dirksen Parkway P.O. Box 1715 Peoria, IL 61607
Questions? Call toll-free 1.800.633.7077 or go to cefcu.com.
Who we are
Who is providing this California Privacy Policy? CEFCU and CEFCU Financial Services, Inc.
What we do
How does CEFCU protect my personal information?
To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards, secured files and buildings, and restricted access to your personal information.
How does CEFCU collect my personal information?
We collect your personal information, for example, when you:
open an account or deposit money
apply for insurance
pay your bills or apply for a loan
pay insurance premiums
use your credit or debit card
We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.
Why can’t I limit all sharing?
Federal law gives you the right to limit only:
sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your creditworthiness
affiliates from using your information to market to you
sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you
State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.
See below for more on your rights under state law.
What happens when I limit sharing for an account/policy I hold jointly with someone else?
Your choices will apply to everyone on your account/policy – unless you tell us otherwise.
Definitions
Affiliates
Companies related by common ownership or control: They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.
Our affiliates are:
CEFCU Financial Services, Inc.
MEMBERS™ Trust Company
Nonaffiliates
Companies not related by common ownership or control: They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.
Nonaffiliates we share with can include financial service providers, such as securities broker-dealers and insurance companies or agents; and non-financial companies, such as retailers, direct marketing companies, airlines, and publishers.
Joint marketing
A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.
Our joint marketing partners include securities broker-dealers and insurance companies.
Other Important Information
California law limits our sharing your personal and financial information: (1) with a nonaffiliated third party unless you give us your prior written consent; and (2) with our affiliates or with outside companies we enter into joint marketing with to provide products and services unless we give you an “Important Privacy Choices for Consumers” notice and you do not say “No”.  The “Important Privacy Choices for Consumers” notice is provided at the time you open your account and sent to you annually.
Security Procedures
We understand the confidential and secure nature of your personal and financial data and have multiple security measures in place. Applications for services, account(s) or loan(s) that you submit through Online Banking, Open an Account, or Apply for a Loan and forms that you complete and submit on our website are submitted through secure, encrypted web pages. You can verify the security of a web page by looking for the “locked padlock” icon which most browsers display as a sign of a secure web page. To ensure the encryption of your web visit, you should ensure that you are using the most current web browser available. When you have logged in to Online Banking, Open an Account, or Apply for a Loan, all transactions and information are secure. We utilize the latest in technology to monitor Online Banking, Open an Account, and Apply for a Loan activity to protect your transactions and information. Built-in security measures include a session time-out (your Online Banking, Open an Account, or Apply for a Loan session will automatically log out after a period of inactivity), log in error lockout (after repeated incorrect log in attempts), and multi-factor authentication to verify your identity before you can log in.
Cookies
In order to provide certain Web-based services and to make your online experience more personalized, we may use cookies as part of our interaction with your Internet browser. A cookie is a very small piece of information stored on your local computer so it can later be read by our Web server. We use cookies to display information more effectively to you and to gather data about usage of our website. Cookies allow us to collect technical and navigational information — such as browser type, time spent on our website, and pages visited or track activity relating to our online promotions. This information is anonymous and does not include personal information. We retain, aggregate, monitor, and analyze the use of our website so we can continually improve the design, usability, and functionality to better serve you.
You can disable and delete cookies by accessing your browser’s preferences menu; however, you should be aware that when cookies are disabled, other online account services we provide, like Online Banking, may not work properly. For more information on working with cookies, consult the Help function of your browser.
Links to Other Websites
We are committed to providing you with the most complete information possible to help you make sound financial decisions. As a convenience to you, we may link from our website to other websites or Internet resources operated by third parties. When you link from our website to a third-party website, the linked website will appear in a new browser window or an alert will appear to notify you that you are leaving our website.
Links to third-party websites are solely for informational purposes and should not be construed as our endorsement or guarantee of the information or services provided on the linked website. We do not control third-party websites and are not responsible for the content on linked websites. Third-party website privacy, security, and other policies may differ from this California Privacy Policy. Please review a linked website’s policies before providing personal information on that website.
Information Collection
We do not collect any personally identifiable information on our website unless you submit the information or give your consent. We use website monitoring software to gather aggregate information about our visitors’ browsing activities in order to improve our website and better serve our members/consumers. We use this data to analyze trends, track visitor movement, and gather demographic information. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. We provide calculators and other online tools to assist visitors in making financial decisions. These tools do not collect or store any information entered by web visitors. Applications for services, accounts, or loans you submit through Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan and forms that you complete and submit on our website are protected in accord with this California Privacy Policy.
We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under age 13 on our website.
When you log in to Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan, your identity is no longer anonymous; each username corresponds to a specific member/consumer and that information is collected and retained. To ensure the security of your accounts and information, all actions are monitored and tracked. You should never share your username and/or password with another person to ensure the security and privacy of your accounts and information. Refer to the Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan disclosures for complete privacy, security, and usage information.
Information We Collect
As hereinafter referred to in this California Privacy Policy, “personal information” means information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer, household, or device.  Personal information does not include:
Publicly available information from government records.
Deidentified or aggregated consumer information.
Information excluded from the CCPA’s scope, like:
health or medical information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA) or clinical trial data;
personal information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994.
Below is a list of categories of personal information specified in the CCPA and an indication whether or not we have collected that information about individual consumers through our website, online services, or otherwise within the last 12 months:
Category
Examples
Collected
A. Identifiers.
A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, internet protocol address, email address, account name, Social Security number, driver’s license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers.
YES
B. Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)).
A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information.
Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories.
YES
C. Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.
Age (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information).
YES
D. Commercial information.
Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.
YES
E. Biometric information.
Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as, fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data.
NO
F. Internet or other electronic network activity information.
Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a website, application, or advertisement.
YES
G. Geolocation data.
Physical location or movements.
YES
H. Sensory data.
Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information.
YES
I. Professional or employment-related information.
Current or past job history or performance evaluations.
YES
J. Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. § 1232g; 34 C.F.R. Part 99)).
Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records.
NO
K. Inferences drawn from other personal information.
Profile reflecting a person’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.
YES
For each category of personal information collected in the preceding 12 months, the categories of sources from which that personal information was collected, the business or commercial purpose(s) for which that personal information was collected, and the categories of third parties with whom we share that personal information are as follows:
Category
Categories of sources from which personal information was collected
Business or commercial purpose(s) for which personal information was collected
Categories of third parties with whom personal information was shared
A. Identifiers.
Directly from you.  For example, from applications and forms provided by us or on our website that you begin and/or complete and submit to us.
Indirectly from you. For example, from interaction with our website, communications with us in person, by telephone, email and/or in writing and your communications about us on social media.
From other financial companies and our affiliates.
For any of the uses listed under “Use of Personal Information” below.
Other financial companies and our affiliates.
B. Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)).
Directly from you.  For example, from applications and forms provided by us or on our website that you begin and/or complete and submit to us.
Indirectly from you. For example, from interaction with our website, communications with us in person, by telephone, email and/or in writing and your communications about us on social media.
From other financial companies and our affiliates.
For any of the uses listed under “Use of Personal Information” below.
Other financial companies and our affiliates.
C. Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.
Directly from you.  For example, from your mortgage and home equity loan and line of credit applications and forms provided by us or on our website that you begin and/or complete and submit to us.
For the purpose for which you provided the information.
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus and governmental agencies.
Governmental agencies.
D. Commercial information.
Directly from you.  For example, from applications and forms for loans, accounts, and services you begin and/or complete and submit to us.
Indirectly from you. For example, from credit bureaus
For the purpose for which you provided the information.
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus and governmental agencies.
Other financial companies and our affiliates.
F. Internet or other electronic network activity information.
Indirectly from you. For example, from interaction with our website.
To provide you with products and services.
To verify your identity, such as when you access your account or your account information, and to help prevent fraud on your account.
None.
G. Geolocation data.
Directly from you.  For example, when you register for credit and/or debit card alerts.
Indirectly from you.  For example, when you visit our website.
To verify your identity, such as when you access your account or your account information, and to help prevent fraud on your account.
To track your location so we can direct you to our nearest Member Center or ATM.
None.
H. Sensory data.
Indirectly from you. For example, from your phone calls to our Member Center or Contact Center and your personal visits to our Member Center or ATMs.
To verify your identity, such as when you access your account or your account information, and to help prevent fraud on your account.
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus and governmental agencies.
None.
I. Professional or employment-related information.
Directly from you.  For example, from applications and forms provided by us or on our website that you begin and/or complete and submit to us.
For any of the uses listed under “Use of Personal Information” below.
Other financial companies and our affiliates.
K. Inferences drawn from other personal information.
Indirectly from you. For example, from interaction with our website.
For our marketing purposes – to offer our products and services to you, including using your behavior to shape messages you see for displaying advertising.
None.
Use of Personal Information
We may use or disclose the personal information we collect for one or more of the following purposes:
For the purpose for which you provided the information. For example, if you share your name and contact information to ask a question about our products or services, we will use that personal information to respond to your inquiry. If you provide your personal information to open an account, we will use that information to open your account. We may also save your information to facilitate providing services to you.
To provide you with products and services.
For our everyday business purposes – such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus and governmental agencies.
To provide you with support and to respond to your inquiries, including to investigate and address your concerns.
To evaluate or conduct a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us is among the assets transferred.
To verify your identity, such as when you access your account or your account information, and to help prevent fraud on your account.
To send you important information regarding our website, change in terms, conditions and/or policies.
For our marketing purposes – to offer our products and services to you, including using behavior to shape messages you see for displaying advertising.
For joint marketing with other financial companies and our affiliates.
To track your location so we can direct you to our nearest Member Center or ATM.
As described to you when collecting your personal information or as otherwise set forth in the CCPA.
We will not collect additional categories of personal information or use the personal information we collected for materially different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.
Sharing Personal Information
We may disclose your personal information to a third party for a business purpose. When we disclose personal information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract.
Disclosures of Personal Information for a Business Purpose
In the preceding 12 months, we have disclosed the following categories of personal information to third parties for a business purpose:
Category A: Identifiers.
Category B: California Customer Records personal information categories.
Category C: Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.
Category D: Commercial information.
Category I: Professional or employment-related information.
We disclose your personal information for a business purpose to the following categories of third parties:
Other financial companies.
Our affiliates.
Sales of Personal Information
We have not sold personal information of any consumers in the preceding 12 months, and we will not sell personal information of any consumers in the future.
Your Rights and Choices
The CCPA provides consumers with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and explains how to exercise those rights.
Access to Specific Information and Data Portability Rights
You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request (see Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights), we will disclose to you:
The categories of personal information we collected about you.
The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.
Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that personal information.
The categories of third parties with whom we share that personal information.
The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).
If we sold your personal information or disclosed it for a business purpose, two separate lists disclosing:
the categories of personal information that we sold about you and the categories of third parties to whom the personal information was sold, by category or categories of personal information for each category of third parties to whom the personal information was sold; and
the categories of personal information that we disclosed about you for a business purpose and the categories of third parties to whom the personal information was disclosed for a business purpose, by category or categories of personal information for each category of third parties to whom the personal information was disclosed for a business purpose.
Deletion Request Rights
You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request (see Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights), we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies.
We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service provider(s) to:
Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, fulfill the terms of a written warranty or product recall conducted in accordance with federal law, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise that consumer’s free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 seq.).
Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information’s deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research’s achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
Comply with a legal obligation.
Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.
Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights
To exercise the access, data portability, and deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable consumer request to us by either:
Calling us at 1-888-556-7376.
Visiting https://www.cefcu.com/forms/contact/ccpa
Only you, or someone legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child.  You can designate an authorized agent to make a request under the CCPA on your behalf by granting the authorized agent written permission to do so (in which case we may require you to verify your identity directly to us) or by providing the authorized agent with power of attorney pursuant to California Probate Code sections 4000 to 4465.
You may only make a verifiable consumer request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period.
The verifiable consumer request to exercise access, data portability, or deletion rights must:
Provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative, which may include:
Account Number (if current member)
ID Number (if current member)
Name
Address
Date of Birth
Phone Number
Place of Employment
A signed declaration under penalty of perjury that the requestor is the consumer whose personal information is the subject of the request if we are unable to successfully verify your identity
Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.
We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you.
Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we do consider requests made through your password protected account sufficiently verified when the request relates to personal information associated with that specific account.
We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.
Response Timing and Format
We will confirm receipt of a verifiable consumer request within 10 days of our receipt of the verifiable consumer request and provide information about our verification process and when you should expect a response, except in instances where we have already granted or denied the request. We endeavor to respond to a verifiable consumer request within 45 days of its receipt. If we require more time, we will inform you of the reason and extension period (which can be up to 90 days from receipt) in writing.
If you have an account with us, we will deliver our written response to that account. If you do not have an account with us, we will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.
Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding the verifiable consumer request’s receipt. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance.
We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable consumer request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.
Non-Discrimination
For exercising any of your rights under the CCPA, we will not discriminate against you by:
Denying you goods or services.
Charging you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
Providing you a different level or quality of goods or services.
Suggesting that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
We do not currently provide financial incentives for the collection, sale, or deletion of personal information.  However, the CCPA allows us to offer you certain financial incentives permitted by the CCPA that could result in different prices, rates, or quality levels. Any CCPA-permitted financial incentive we might offer in the future would reasonably relate to your personal information’s value and contain written terms that describe the program’s material aspects. Participation in a financial incentive program that we might offer in the future requires your prior opt in consent, which you may revoke at any time.
Other California Privacy Rights
California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code § 1798.83) permits users of our website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to dirrera@cefcu.com or write us at: Citizens Equity First Credit Union, Compliance Department, P.O. Box 1715, Peoria, IL 61656-9989.
In accordance with the requirements of the California Online Privacy Protection Act (Business and Professions Code §§ 22575 to 22579), we disclose the following:
CEFCU's first-party, proprietary software does not capture personally-identifiable information unless the user is prompted (e.g. forms inquiring about personal information in order to open accounts, set appointments with Member Centers, etc.). Although CEFCU does not control how third-party software tracks personally-identifiable information, we work closely with our third-party providers to ensure members’ (and non-members') information is secure. Such third-party software include our Online Loan Application and Online Banking.
CEFCU's first-party, proprietary software does not share personally-identifiable information with other parties. Although CEFCU does not control how third-party software shares personally-identifiable information with outside parties, we work closely with our third-party providers to ensure members' (and non-members') information is secure.
Interruption of Service
At certain times, cefcu.com, Online Banking, Open an Account, and/or Apply for a Loan may be unavailable due to system maintenance or circumstances beyond our control. We conduct frequent and regular backups of your information and utilize redundant information practices to protect your information from being lost, altered, or corrupted due to unforeseen equipment malfunctions.
Changes to California Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to amend this California Privacy Policy at our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this California Privacy Policy, we will post the updated California Privacy Policy on our website and update the effective date. Your continued use of our website or any product or service we provide following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.
Contact Information
If you have any questions or comments about this California Privacy Policy, the ways in which we collect and use your information described here, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California law, please contact us at:
Phone: 1-888-556-7376
Postal Address:
Citizens Equity First Credit Union             Compliance Department             P.O. Box 1715             Peoria, IL 61656-9989
Effective Date: January 1, 2020.
Last Reviewed on: December 31, 2019
